export const eCLOSEST = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: `<p> Mai <u>enjoys</u> making crafts, especially bracelets.</p>`,
    options: [
      `<p><strong>A.</strong> adores</p>`,
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> hates</p>`,
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> detests</p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> dislikes</p>`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `<p><strong>Kiến thức:</strong> Từ đồng nghĩa</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>enjoy (v): thích</p>

<p>A. adores (v): thích                  </p><p>B. hates (v): ghét</p><p>C. detests (v): ghét                  </p><p>D. dislikes (v): không thích</p><p>=&gt; enjoy (v) = adore (v): thích</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch:</strong> Mai rất thích làm đồ thủ công, đặc biệt là vòng tay.</p><p><strong>Chọn A. </strong></p>`,
  },

  {
    id: 2,
    question: `<p> Gardening and hunting still play an <u>important</u> role in the economy of the Laha.</p>
    `,
    options: [
      `<p><strong>A.</strong> convenient</p>`,
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> significant</p>`,
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> complicated</p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> developed</p>`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `<p><strong>Kiến thức:</strong> Từ đồng nghĩa</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>important (adj): quan trọng</p><p>A. convenient (adj): thuận tiện       </p><p>B. significant (adj): quan trọng, đáng kể</p>

<p>C. complicated (adj): phức tạp        </p><p>D. developed (adj): phát triển</p><p>=&gt; important (adj) = significant (adj): quan trọng</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch:</strong> Làm vườn và săn bắn vẫn đóng một vai trò quan trọng trong nền kinh tế của người Laha.</p><p><strong>Chọn B. </strong></p>`,
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: `<p> They raise <u>cows, buffaloes</u> for their own use.</p> `,
    options: [
      `<p><strong>A.</strong> crops </p>`,
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> poultry </p>`,
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> harvest</p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> cattle</p>`,
    ],
    answer: `4`,
    explanation: `<p>
      <strong>Kiến thức:</strong> Từ đồng nghĩa
    </p><p>
      <strong>Giải thích: </strong>
    </p><p>cows, buffaloes: bò, trâu</p><p>A. crops (n): vụ mùa </p><p>B. poultry (n): gia cầm</p><p>C. harvest (n): thu hoạch, vụ gặt </p><p>D. cattle (n): gia súc</p><p>=&gt; cows, buffaloes: bò, trâu = cattle (n): gia súc</p><p>
      <strong>Tạm dịch:</strong> Họ chăn nuôi bò, trâu với mục đích riêng
      của họ.
    </p><p>
      <strong>Chọn D.</strong>
    </p>`,
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: `<p> The Muong in Hoa Binh and Thanh Hoa are <u>well-known</u> for their rich folk literature and their traditional songs.</p> `,
    options: [
      `<p><strong>A.</strong> famous </p>`,
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> significant </p>`,
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> major </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> convenient</p>`,
    ],
    answer: `1`,
    explanation: `<p>
      <strong>Kiến thức:</strong> Từ đồng nghĩa
    </p><p>
      <strong>Giải thích: </strong>
    </p><p>well-known (adj): nổi tiếng</p><p>A. famous (adj): nổi tiếng </p><p>B. significant (adj): đáng kể, quan trọng</p><p>C. major (adj): chủ yếu </p><p>D. convenient (adj): thuận tiện, thuận lợi</p><p>=&gt; well-known (adj) = famous (adj): nổi tiếng</p><p>
      <strong>Tạm dịch:</strong> Người Mường ở Hòa Bình và Thanh Hóa nổi
      tiếng với nền văn học dân gian phong phú và các bài hát truyền thống
      của họ.
    </p><p>
      <strong>Chọn A.</strong>
    </p>`,
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: `<p><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>21. The</strong> Thai are <strong><u>experienced</u></strong> farmers. They grow different crops.</span></p> `,
    options: [
      `<p><span style="color: #000000;">A. bad</span></p>`,
      `<p><span style="color: #000000;">B. better</span></p>`,
      `<p><span style="color: #000000;">C. worse</span></p>`,
      `<p><span style="color: #000000;">D. good</span></p>`,
    ],
    answer: `4`,
    explanation: `<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ đồng nghĩa</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>experienced (adj): giàu kinh nghiệm</p><p>A. bad (adj): xấu, tệ          B. better: tốt hơn</p><p>C. worse: xấu hơn, tệ hơn      D. good (adj): tốt, giỏi</p><p>=&gt; experienced (adj): giàu kinh nghiệm = good (adj): tốt, giỏi</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Người Thái là những nông dân giàu kinh nghiệm. Họ trồng các loại cây trồng khác nhau.</p><p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p>`,
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: `<p><span style="color: #000000;"> The northwest region of Viet Nam is <strong><u>famous</u></strong> for breathtaking rice terraced paddy fields.</span></p> `,
    options: [
      `<p><span style="color: #000000;">A. fabulous</span></p>`,
      `<p><span style="color: #000000;">B. well- known</span></p>`,
      `<p><span style="color: #000000;">C. surprised</span></p>`,
      `<p><span style="color: #000000;">D. interesting</span></p>`,
    ],
    answer: `2`,
    explanation: `<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ đồng nghĩa</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>famous (adj): nổi tiếng</p><p>A. fabulous (adj): thần thoại, bịa đặt, hoang đường</p><p>B. well- known (adj): nổi tiếng</p><p>C. surprised (adj): ngạc nhiên</p><p>D. interesting (adj): thú vị</p><p>=&gt; famous (adj) = well- known (adj): nổi tiếng</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Khu vực Tây Bắc của Việt Nam nổi tiếng với những ruộng lúa bậc thang ngoạn mục.</p><p><strong>Chọn B.</strong></p>`,
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: `<p>We move two or three times a year to look for new <strong><u>pastures</u></strong>.</p>
    `,
    options: [
      `<strong>A.</strong> grasslands         `,
      `<strong>B.</strong> cattle`,
      `<strong>C.</strong> products `,
      `<strong>D.</strong> mountains`,
    ],
    answer: `1`,
    explanation: `<p><strong>Kiến thức:</strong> Từ đồng nghĩa</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>pastures (n): đồng cỏ</p><p>A. grasslands (n): đồng cỏ           B. cattle (n): gia súc</p><p>C. products (n): sản phẩm           D. mountains (n): núi</p><p>=&gt; pasture (n) = grassland (n): đồng cỏ</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch:</strong> Chúng tôi di chuyển hai hoặc ba lần một năm để tìm kiếm đồng cỏ mới.</p><p><strong>Chọn A.</strong></p>`,
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: `<p> The students <strong><u>ought to</u></strong> learn their lessons carefully before the exams.</p>
        `,
    options: [
      `<strong>A.</strong> will       `,
      `<strong>B.</strong> should `,
      `<strong>C.</strong> must `,
      `<strong>D.</strong> have to <strong><em></em></strong>`,
    ],
    answer: `2`,
    explanation: `<p><strong>Kiến thức:</strong> Từ đồng nghĩa<strong> </strong></p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>ought to: nên làm gì</p><p>A. will: sẽ                       B. should: nên</p><p>C. must: phải                    D. have to: phải</p><p>=&gt; ought to = should: nên</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch:</strong> Học sinh nên học bài cẩn thận trước khi thi.</p><p><strong>Chọn B.</strong></p>`,
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: `Scientific <b>progress</b> brings us many conveniences and advanced machines, such as computers, automobiles, and so on.

  `,
    options: [
      `job
`,
      `achievement
`,
      `failure
`,
      `responsibility
`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `<div>
                            <p>Scientific <strong>progress</strong> brings us many conveniences and advanced machines, such as computers, automobiles, and so on.</p>
<p><span style="color: #808080;"><em>(<span style="text-decoration: underline;">Tiến bộ</span> khoa học mang lại cho chúng ta nhiều tiện ích và máy móc tiên tiến như máy vi tính, ô tô, v.v.)</em></span></p>
<p>job (n): <em>công việc</em></p>
<p>achievement (n):<em> thành tựu</em></p>
<p>failure (n): <em>thất bại</em></p>
<p>responsibility (n):<em> trách nhiệm</em></p>
<p>=&gt; progress = achievement</p>                        </div>`,
  }, //https://vietjack.com/trac-nghiem-tieng-anh/100-cau-trac-nghiem-tu-dong-nghia-co-dap-an-co-ban.jsp
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `I didn’t think his the comments were
        very <u>appropriate</u> at the time.
  `,
    options: [
      `correct  `,
      `right  `,
      `exact
         `,
      `suitable
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `appropriate = suitable (a) thích hợp`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `GCSE are not <u>compulsory</u>, but
        they are the most common qualifications taken by students.`,
    options: [`required  `, `applied  `, ` fulfilled  `, `specialized`],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `compulsory = required (a) bắt buộc, được yêu cầu`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` I received housing benefit when I was
        <u>unemployed</u>.
    `,
    options: [
      `out of order `,
      `out of fashion `,
      `
        out of work  `,
      `out of practice
      `,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `unemployed = out of work (a) thất nghiệp`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` The related publications are far too
        <u>numerous</u> to list individually.`,
    options: [
      `much  `,
      `legion  `,
      `few
         `,
      `full`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `numerous = much (a) nhiều`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The teacher gave some
        <u>suggestions</u> on what would come out for the examination.
    `,
    options: [
      `symptoms  `,
      `demonstrations `,
      `
        effects  `,
      `hints
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `suggestion = hint (n) lời gợi ý`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `When being interviewed, you should
        <u>concentrate</u> on what the interviewer is saying or asking you.`,
    options: [
      `relate on  `,
      `be interested in 
        `,
      `impress on  `,
      `pay attention to`,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `concentrate on st = pat attention to st (v) chú ý đến
            cái gì`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `She came to the meeting late
        <u>on purpose</u> so she would miss the introductory speech.
    `,
    options: [
      `aiming at  `,
      `intentionally  `,
      `
        reasonably  `,
      `with a goal
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `on purpose = with a goal (adv) có mục đích`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The use of lasers in surgery has
        become <u>relatively</u> commonplace in recent years.`,
    options: [
      `comparatively  `,
      `relevantly  `,
      `
        absolutely  `,
      `almost`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `relatively = comparatively (adv) tương đối`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The first few days at university can
        be very <u>daunting</u>, but with determination and positive attitude,
        freshmen will soon fit in with the new environment.
    `,
    options: [
      `interesting  `,
      `memorable  `,
      `
        serious  `,
      `depressing
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `daunting = depressing (a) làm chán nản`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Did anyone <u>acknowledge</u>
        responsibility for the outbreak of the fire ?`,
    options: [
      `inquire about `,
      `accept  C.
        report  `,
      `find out`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `acknowledge = accept (v) thừa nhận`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `<u> Childbearing</u> is the women's
        most wonderful role.
    `,
    options: [
      `Giving birth to a baby  `,
      `Bring up a child
         `,
      `Educating a child  `,
      `Having no
        child
      `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `Childbearing = giving birth to a baby (sự sinh đẻ)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `In my experience, <u>freshmen</u>
        today are different from those I knew 25 years ago.`,
    options: [
      `first-year students `,
      `new students
         `,
      `new counselors `,
      `young
        professors`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `freshman = first-year student (n) sinh viên năm nhất`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `S. Mayo Hospital in New Orleans was
        so named in recognition of Dr. Mayo’s <u>outstanding</u>
        humanitarianism.
      `,
    options: [
      `unpopular  `,
      `widespread  `,
      `
        remarkable  `,
      `charitable
      `,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `outstanding = remarkable (a) nổi bật, đáng chú ý`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `My parents’ warnings didn’t
        <u>deter</u> me from choosing the job of my dreams.`,
    options: [
      `influence  `,
      `discourage  `,
      `
        reassure  `,
      `inspire`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `deter = discourage (v) ngăn cản, làm nhụt chí`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` “It’s no use talking to me about
        metaphysics. It’s <u>a closed book to me</u>.”
      `,
    options: [
      `a subject that I don’t understand  `,
      `a theme that
        I like to discuss`,
      `a book that is never opened  `,
      `an object that I
        really love
      `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `a closed book to me = a subject that I don’t understand
            (một chủ đề tôi không hề biết gì về nó)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Professor Berg was very interested in
        the <u>diversity</u> of cultures all over the world.`,
    options: [
      `variety `,
      `changes  `,
      `
        conservation `,
      `number`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `diversity = veariety (n) tính đa dạng`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The situation seems to be changing
        <u>minute by minute</u>.
      `,
    options: [
      `again and again `,
      `time after
        time `,
      `very rapidly `,
      `frOm time to
        time
      `,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `minute by minute. = very rapidly (adv) từng phút/ rất
            nhanh`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` If desired, <u>garnish</u> your
        plate with parsley, bell pepper rings or other vegetables`,
    options: [
      `decorate  `,
      `replace `,
      `
        associate  `,
      `provide`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `garnish = decorate (v) bày biện, trang trí`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The bomb <u>exploded</u> in the
        garage; fortunately no one hurt.
      `,
    options: [
      `taken off `,
      `went off `,
      `put on
         `,
      `hold up
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `explode = go off (v) nổ (bom)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `In times of war, the Red Cross is
        <u>dedicated</u> to reducing the sufferings of wounded soldiers,
        civilians, and prisoners of war.`,
    options: [
      `initiated `,
      `appalled  `,
      `devoted
         `,
      `mounted`,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `dedicate = devote (v) cống hiến`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Sorry, I can’t come to your party. I
        am <u>snowed under</u> with work at the moment.
      `,
    options: [
      `interested in `,
      `busy with  `,
      `
        relaxed about `,
      `free from
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `be snowed under st = be bust with st (bận bịu với việc
            gì)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The consequences of the typhoon were
        <u>disatrous</u> due to the lack of effective measures.`,
    options: [
      `meaningful  `,
      `beneficial  `,
      `
        excited  `,
      `damaging`,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `disetrous = damaging (a) có sức tàn phá`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `He’s really <u>delighted</u> with
        his success.
        `,
    options: [
      `pleased  `,
      `angry  `,
      `entertained
         `,
      `annoyed
      `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `delighted = pleased (a) hài lòng`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Try to <u>eliminate</u> fatty foods
        from your diet.`,
    options: [
      `limit  `,
      `move  `,
      `add
         `,
      `get rid of `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `eliminate = get rid of (v) loại ra`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` No vehicle weighing over 3.5 tons is
        allowed on this bridge, according to traffic signs placed at both ends
        of the <u>structure</u>
        `,
    options: [
      `corruption  `,
      `construction  `,
      `
        connection  `,
      `confusion
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `strcuture = construction (n) cấu trúc`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Ask Mum for permission to go out
        now. She looks like she’s <u>in a good mood</u>.`,
    options: [
      `fashionable `,
      `unconcerned `,
      `
        healthful  `,
      `happy`,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `be in a good mood = happy (a) trong trạng thái tốt, vui
            vẻ`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The Asian Games have <u>advanced</u>
        in all aspects since the first Games was help in 1951.
        `,
    options: [
      `developed  `,
      `competed  `,
      `taken
        place  `,
      `decrease
      `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `advance = develop (v) phát triển, tiến bộ`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Dozens of applicants showed up for
        the vacant position, but only <u>a handful</u> of them were shortlisted
        for the interview.`,
    options: [
      `small amount `,
      `person  `,
      `hand
         `,
      `small number`,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `a handful = small number/ small amount (một ít …). Tuy
            nhiên câu hỏi này danh từ chính là ‘applicants’ (đếm được)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` He made one last <u>futile</u>
        effort to convince her and left home.
        `,
    options: [
      `favorable  `,
      `difficult  `,
      `
        ineffectual  `,
      `firm
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `futile = ineffectual (a) không hiệu quả`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `He <u>resembles</u> his brother in
        appearance very much, which makes his friends unable to recognize`,
    options: [
      `names after  `,
      `calls after  `,
      `
        looks after  `,
      `takes after`,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `resemble = take after (v) giống`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Sports and festivals form an
        <u>integral</u> part of every human society.
        `,
    options: [
      `delighted  `,
      `exciting  `,
      `
        informative  `,
      `essential
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `intergral = essential (a) cần thiết, không thể thiếu`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `As tourism is more developed, people
        worry about the damage to the <u>flora and fauna</u> of the island.`,
    options: [
      `fruits and vegetables  `,
      `flowers and trees `,
      `plants and animals  `,
      `mountains and forest`,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `flora and fauna (động thực vật) = plants and animals
            (thực vật và động vật)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `It’s a really difficult matter to
        decide how to solve now. I will need time to <u>think it twice.</u>
          `,
    options: [
      `to think it over  `,
      `to make it better`,
      `to make up for it  `,
      `to think out of time
      `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `think twice = think over (v) nghĩ kĩ`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` He insisted on listening to the
        <u>entire</u> story.`,
    options: [
      `part  `,
      `funny  `,
      `whole
         `,
      `interesting`,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: ` entire = whole (a) toàn bộ`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` We can use either <u>verbal</u> or
        nonverbal forms of communication.
          `,
    options: [
      `using gesture  `,
      `using speech `,
      `using verbs  `,
      `using facial expressions
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `verbal = using speech (a) sử dụng lời nói`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The education system is a mirror
        that <u>reflects</u> the culture.`,
    options: [
      `points  `,
      `explains  `,
      `shows
         `,
      `gets`,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `reflect = show (v) phản chiếu, biểu lộ`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `It is an occasion when
        <u>strength</u> and sports are tested, friendship and solidarity was
        built and deepened.
          `,
    options: [
      `practice `,
      `power `,
      `will
         `,
      `competence
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: ` strenth = power (n) sức mạnh`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Nobody knows the origin of the
        Vietnamese long dress. There was no <u>evidence</u> about where and when
        it appeared.`,
    options: [
      `evaluation  `,
      `book  `,
      `proof
         `,
      `symptom`,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `evidence = proof (n) bằng chứng`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The shop assistant was totally
        <u>bewildered</u> by the customer’s behavior.
          `,
    options: [
      `disgusted  `,
      `puzzled  `,
      `angry
         `,
      `upset
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: ` bewildered = puzzled (a) bị làm cho bối rối`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Reaching 35 and obviously aging,
        Jane has to <u>make up her mind</u> on her future very soon.`,
    options: [
      `give a thought about  `,
      `pay attention to `,
      `prepare a plan for  `,
      `make a decision on `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `make up sb’s mind = make a decision (v) đưa ra quyết
            định`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` How many countries <u>took part</u>
        in the last Olympic Games?
          `,
    options: [
      `participated  `,
      `performed  `,
      `
        succeeded  `,
      `hosted
      `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `take part in = participate in (v) tham gia`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `<u>Mobile</u> libraries brings books
        to children in many small communities. These libraries travel from towns
        to towns in cars, vans, or trucks.`,
    options: [
      `Moving from place to place`,
      `Changing shape or expression easily and frequently`,
      `Being bent easily and quickly`,
      `Staying in one place`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `mobile = moving from place to place (di động)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The whole village was
        <u>wiped out</u> in the bombing raids.
            `,
    options: [
      `cleaned well  `,
      `changed completely`,
      `removed quickly  `,
      `destroyed completely
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `be wiped out = be destroyed (bị tàn phá)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Whenver problems <u>come up</u>, we
        discuss them frankly and find solutions quickly`,
    options: [
      `clean `,
      `encounter  `,
      `arrive
         `,
      `happen`,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `come up = happen (v) xảy ra`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` You never really know where you are
        with her as she just <u>blows hot and cold</u>.
            `,
    options: [
      `keeps going  `,
      `keeps taking things `,
      `keeps changing her mood  `,
      `keeps testing
      `,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `blow hot and cold = keep changing sb’s mood (v) thay đổi
            cảm xúc liên tục`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `These were the people who
        <u>advocated</u> using force to stop school violence.`,
    options: [
      `publicly supported  `,
      `openly criticized `,
      `publicly said  `,
      `strongly condemned`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `advocated = publicly supported (a) công khai ủng hộ`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` When preparing <u>a diet</u>, a
        person should be aware that vitamin D acts to increase the amount of
        calcium absorbed by the body.
            `,
    options: [
      `schedule of exercise  `,
      `medicinal chart`,
      `study of longevity  `,
      `nutritional plan
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `diet = nutritional plan (n) chế độ ăn kiêng`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `If you do not understand the word
        "superstitious", <u>look it up</u> in the dictionary.`,
    options: [
      `write it  `,
      `note it  `,
      `find its
        meaning  `,
      `draw it`,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `look up = find meaning (tra cứu từ - bằng từ điển) `,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Now <u>I understand</u> why you moved
        out of that house.
            `,
    options: [
      `I am surprised  `,
      `it frustrates me`,
      `I am intrigued  `,
      `it makes sense to me
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `understand = make sense (v) hiểu`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Flight MH370 of Malaysia Airlines is
        reported to <u>vanish</u> on the way from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing.`,
    options: [
      `land  `,
      `control  `,
      `cancel
         `,
      `disappear`,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `vanish = disappear (v) tan biến, biến mất`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `People are busy buying gifts,
        cleaning and decorating the house and cooking <u>traditional</u> foods
        to welcome Tet holiday now.
            `,
    options: [
      `favorite  `,
      `important  `,
      `
        customary  `,
      `national
      `,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `traditional = custromary (a) có tính truyền thống`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Many new graduates take a part –
        time job and barely <u>make ends meet</u> every month.`,
    options: [
      `become a professional  `,
      `earn enough to live `,
      `put aside extra money  `,
      `balance study and work`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `make ends meet = earn enough to live (v) kiếm đủ để sống`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Although we argued with him for a
        long time, he <u>stood his ground</u>.
              `,
    options: [
      `felt sorry for us  `,
      `changed his decision `,
      `wanted to continue  `,
      `refused to change his
        decision
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `stand sb’s ground = refuse to change decision (v) giữ
            vững lập trường`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` You can <u>make a good living</u> in
        sales if you have the right attitude and strategies.`,
    options: [
      `achieve consideration success  `,
      `earn a lot of
        money `,
      `have an uncomfortable lifestyle  `,
      `live a good
        life`,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `make a good living = live a good life (v) sống cuộc sống
            tốt`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Most ethnic groups in Vetnam have
        their own costumes that reflect their <u>unique</u> culture identities
              `,
    options: [
      `invaluable  `,
      `different  `,
      `
        distinctive  `,
      `important
      `,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `unique = distinctive (a) đặc biệt, độc nhất vô nhị`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Fallout from a nuclear power station
        <u>damaged</u> in the tsunami may endanger the vegetation.`,
    options: [
      `stimulate `,
      `harm  `,
      `inhibit
         `,
      `benefit`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `damaged = harm (gây hại)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` He was asked to <u>account for</u>
        his presence at the scene of crime.
              `,
    options: [
      `complain  `,
      `exchange  `,
      `explain
         `,
      `arrange
      `,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `account for = explain (v) giải thích `,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `<u>Participants</u> from 100
        countries go to the Olympic Games`,
    options: [
      `People who represent.  `,
      `People who come `,
      `People who take part in  `,
      `People who are athletes`,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: ` participants = people who take part in (n) người tham
            gia`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` We decided to pay for the car on the
        <u>installment</u> plan.
              `,
    options: [
      `cash and carry  `,
      `monthly payment
         `,
      `credit card  `,
      `piece by piece
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `installment = monthly payment (n) trả góp trả tiền hằng
            tháng`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` I told you clearly and
        <u>definitely</u> not to write your answers in pencil, Smith!`,
    options: [
      `altogether `,
      `specifically  `,
      `
        thoroughly  `,
      `considerably`,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `clearly and definitely: rõ ràng và dứt khoát =
            thoroughly: một cách hoàn toàn`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` I am sure that they will be
        <u>sacked</u> on the spot.
              `,
    options: [
      `employed  `,
      `hired  `,
      `given
         `,
      `fired
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: ` sacked = fired (a) bị sa thải`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `When we went to the airport to
        <u>see her off</u>, we had a traffic jam.`,
    options: [
      `say good bye to her  `,
      `meet her 
        `,
      `take care of her  `,
      `look for her`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `see sb off = say goodbye to sb (v) tạm biệt ai đó`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `This quartet of extraodinarily
        <u>talented</u> musicians generated a phenomenal number of pieces that
        won gold records.
                `,
    options: [
      `irresponsible `,
      `incompetent `,
      `
        stupid  `,
      `crazy
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `talented = imcompetent (a) tài năng/ không đối thủ`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` The journalist refused to
        <u>disclose</u> the sourse of his information.`,
    options: [
      `open  `,
      `reveal  `,
      `shut
         `,
      `conceal `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `disclose = reveal (v) vạch trần, phơi bày`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Around 150 B.C. the Greek astronomer
        Hipparchus developed a system to <u>classify</u> stars according to
        brightness
                `,
    options: [
      `record  `,
      `shine  `,
      `categorize
         `,
      `diversify
      `,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `classify = categorize (v) phân loại`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` The <u>augmentation</u> in the
        population has created a fuel shortage.`,
    options: [
      `increase  `,
      `necesity  `,
      `demand
         `,
      `decrease`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `augmentation = increase (n) sự tăng lên`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `An international medical conference
        <u>initiated</u> by Davison resulted in the birth of the League of Red
        Cross Societies in 1991.
                `,
    options: [
      `treated  `,
      `dedicated  `,
      `helped
         `,
      `started
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `initiated = started (v) bắt đầu`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `He drove so fast that I really felt
        my life was <u>in danger</u>.`,
    options: [
      `at the target `,
      `in accident  `,
      `
        at stake  `,
      `in comfort`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `in danger = in accident (trong tình thế nguy hiểm)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` <u>At last</u>, we succeeded in
        persuading those boys and girls to join our picniC
                `,
    options: [
      `At the end `,
      `In the end  `,
      `
        Lastly  `,
      `Endlessly
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `<p>Giải thích: At last = in the end (cuối cùng)</p>
          <p>
            - at the end: cuối, phía cuối, phần cuối (của cái gì, ví dụ: cuối
            tháng at the end of the month, cuối sự kiện at the end of the
            event,…)
          </p>
          <p>- in the end = finally, eventually = cuối cùng</p>`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` 70. If people’s interference with
        the environment decreases, more species will survive and produce
        <u>offspring</u>.`,
    options: [
      `children  `,
      `ancestor  `,
      `descent
         `,
      `result`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `offsprings = children (n) những đứa con`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Animals on earth <u>fascinate</u> us
        with their beauty, their grace and their speed
                `,
    options: [
      `improve  `,
      `captivate  `,
      `satisfy
         `,
      `amuse
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `fascinate = captivate (v) mê hoặc, thôi miên`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Those companies were <u>closed</u>
        due to some seriously financial problems.`,
    options: [
      `taken off  `,
      `put away  `,
      `gone
        over  `,
      `wiped out`,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `be closed (đóng cửa) = be wiped out (bị xóa sổ)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `John stayed at home from work
        yesterday because he was feeling <u>under the weather</u>.
                  `,
    options: [
      `well  `,
      `sick  `,
      `happy
         `,
      `fine
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: ``,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The cultural and historical sites in
        Kyoto have been given appropriate care and <u>maintenance</u>`,
    options: [
      `preservation `,
      `revival  `,
      `
        recovery  `,
      `recognition`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `maintenance = preservation (n) sự duy trì, sự bảo tồn`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Our parents <u>join hands</u> to give
        us a nice house and a happy home.
                  `,
    options: [
      `make decisions  `,
      `put together `,
      `take each other’s hands  `,
      `work together
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `join hands = work together (v) làm cùng nhau`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Don't be <u>concerned about</u> your
        mother's illness; she'll recover soon.`,
    options: [
      `surprised at  `,
      `worried about 
        `,
      `embarrassed at  `,
      `angry with`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `be concerned about = be worried about (a) lo kawsng về
            cái gì`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The <u>yearly</u> growth of the gross
        national product is often used as an indicator of a nation's economy.
                  `,
    options: [
      `annual  `,
      `irrefutable  `,
      `
        tentative  `,
      `routine
      `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: ` yearly = annual (a) thường niên`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` Many scientists agree that global
        warming poses great <u>threats</u> to all species on Earth.`,
    options: [
      `irritations  `,
      `annoyances  `,
      `
        fears  `,
      `risks `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `threat = risk (n) sự đe dọa`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `During the recession, many small
        companies were <u>eradicated</u>.
                  `,
    options: [
      `taken over  `,
      `wiped out `,
      `run
        on  `,
      `set up
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: ` be eradicated = be wiped out (a) bị xóa sổ`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `It is really <u>incredible</u> that
        he is unaware of such basic facts.`,
    options: [
      `difficult `,
      `unbelievable `,
      `
        imaginable  `,
      `disappointed`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `incredible = unbelievable (a) không thể tin được`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` The twins look so much alike that no
        one can <u>tell them apart</u>.
                  `,
    options: [
      `distinguish between them  `,
      `point out with them`,
      `
      `,
      `spoil them  `,
      `pick them out
      `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `temm apart = distinguish (v) phân biệt`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `<u>With respect to</u>
        maneuverability, few birds can equal the capabilities of the
        hummingbird, which hovers for long periods and even flies backwarD`,
    options: [
      `With regard to `,
      `With fondness
        to `,
      `In appreciation of  `,
      `In
        favor of `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `<p>with respect to = with regard to: đối với, về</p>
          <p>- with fondness to: với sự yêu mến dành cho</p>
          <p>- in appreciation of: trong niềm cảm kích dành cho</p>
          <p>- in favor of: ủng hộ</p>`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The Bali Tiger was declared extinct
        in 1937 due to hunting and <u>habitat</u> loss.
                    `,
    options: [
      `reserve  `,
      `generation  `,
      `
        natural environment `,
      `diversity
      `,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: ` habitat = natural environment (n) môi trường sống`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The shoplifter immediately 
        <u>admitted</u> to her crime to the security guard`,
    options: [
      `Agreed `,
      `Pleased  `,
      `Denied
         `,
      `confessed`,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `admit = confess (v) thừa nhận, thú nhận`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The repeated <u>commercials</u> on
        TV distract many viewers from watching their favorite programmes.
                    `,
    options: [
      `advertisements `,
      `contests  `,
      `
        economics  `,
      `businesses
      `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `commercial = advertisement (n) sự quảng cáo`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `In the twentieth century, drug
        <u>markedly</u> improved health throughout the world`,
    options: [
      `supposedly  `,
      `noticeably  `,
      `
        recently  `,
      `consistently`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `markedly = noticeably (adv) đáng chú ý`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The <u>collapse</u> of the stock
        market in 1929 signaled the beginning of the Depression
                    `,
    options: [
      `debt  `,
      `rebirth  `,
      `rise
         `,
      `failure
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: ` collapse = failure (n) sự thất bại/ sự sụp đổ`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` All classifications of human
        societies and cultures are <u>arbitrary</u>.`,
    options: [
      `useful  `,
      `haphazard  `,
      `
        insufficient  `,
      `ambiguous`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `arbitrary = haphazard (a) chuyên quyền, độc đoán`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `When I mentioned the party, he was 
        <u>all ears</u>.
                    `,
    options: [
      `using both ears  `,
      `listening neglectfull`,
      `listening attentively  `,
      `partially deaf
      `,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `all ears = listening attentively (chú ý lắng nghe cẩn
            thận)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `<u>Once in a while</u> I visit my
        grandparents on the farm and stay there for some days.`,
    options: [
      `Regularly  `,
      `Sometimes  `,
      `
        Usually  `,
      `Rarely`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `once in a while = sometimes (thỉnh thoảng)`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `He had never experienced such 
        <u>discourtesy</u> towards the president as it occurred at the annual
        meeting in May.
                    `,
    options: [
      `politeness `,
      `rudeness  `,
      `
        measurement  `,
      `encouragement
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: ` discourtesy = rudeness (n) sự bất lịch sự`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `In daily communication, you should
        know how to <u>interpret</u> other people’s body language.`,
    options: [
      `understand  `,
      `answer  `,
      `respond
         `,
      `notice`,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `interpret = understand (v) hiểu`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The purpose of this survey is to 
        <u>determine</u> students’ attitudes toward love and marriage.
                      `,
    options: [
      `find out  `,
      `develop  `,
      `concern
         `,
      `build
      `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `determine = find out (v) xác định`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The ages of the two children put
        together was <u>equivalent</u> to that of their father`,
    options: [
      `different  `,
      `corresponding  `,
      `
        unequal  `,
      `temporary`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `equivalent = corresponding (a) tương đương`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `I’m becoming increasingly 
        <u>absent-minded</u>. Last week, I locked myself out of my house twice.
                      `,
    options: [
      `being considerate of things  `,
      `remembering to do
        right things `,
      `forgetful of one’s past  `,
      `often
        forgetting things
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `absent- minded = often forgetting things (a) đãng trí`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The government is not prepared 
        <u>to tolerate</u> this situation any longer.`,
    options: [
      `look down on  `,
      `put up with  `,
      `
        take away from  `,
      `give onto`,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `tolerate = put up with (v) chịu đựng`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `The event, watched by millions of
        people all over the country, takes place <u>annually</u>
                      `,
    options: [
      `sometimes  `,
      `once every year  `,
      `
        regularly  `,
      `smoothly
      `,
    ],
    answer: 2,
    explanation: `annually = once every year (adv) hằng năm`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` The systems caused by ingestion of a
        harmful chemical must be <u>counteracted</u> within minutes in order to
        avoid permanent damage to the kidneys and other vital organs.`,
    options: [
      `alleviated  `,
      `increased  `,
      `
        distributed  `,
      `summed up `,
    ],
    answer: 1,
    explanation: `counteract = alleviate (v) trung hòa, làm giảm`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `An Alzheimer patient’s 
        <u>incomprehensible</u> ramblings will frequently upset family members,
        who may take the statements personally.
                      `,
    options: [
      `rude  `,
      `personal  `,
      `loud
         `,
      `unintelligible
      `,
    ],
    answer: 4,
    explanation: `incomprehensible = unintelligible (a) khó hiểu, không
            thể hiểu nổi`,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: ` I could see the finish line and
        thought I was <u>home and dry</u>.`,
    options: [
      `hopeless  `,
      `hopeful  `,
      `
        successful  `,
      `unsuccessful`,
    ],
    answer: 3,
    explanation: `home and dry = have been successful = thành công`,
  },
  {id:9,
  question: `After the storm, we shouldn't drink water because it can be <u>poisonous</u>.
  `, options:[
      `healthy`,
      `toxic`,
      `fresh`,
      `salty`],
  answer:2,
  explanation:`healthy (adj): khỏe mạnh<br/>
toxic (adj) = poisonous (adj): có độc<br/>
fresh (adj): tươi mới<br/>
salty (adj): mặn<br/>
Tạm dịch: Sau cơn bão, chúng ta không nên uống nước vì nó có thể gây độc.`
  },
  {id:9,
  question: `“We lost the last game because of the referee,” said the team captain.
  `, options:[
      `<p>The team captain said that without the referee, they might have lost the last game.</p>`,
      `<p>The team captain blamed the referee for their loss in the last game.</p>`,
      `<p>The team captain refused to tell the referee about their loss in the last game.</p>`,
      `<p>The team captain admitted to the referee that they had lost in the last game.</p>`],
  answer:2,
  explanation:`blame sb for sth: đổ lỗi cho ai đó về việc gì.<br/>
Tạm dịch: “Chúng tôi đã thua trận gần nhất vì trọng tài,” đội trưởng nói.<br/>
-> Đội trưởng đã đổ lỗi cho trọng tài về bàn thua của họ trong trận đấu gần nhất.<br/>
<div _ngcontent-ng-c2534777750="" class="container-video"><div _ngcontent-ng-c2534777750="" class="title-video ng-star-inserted" style=""> Kiến thức liên quan </div><div _ngcontent-ng-c737685623="" class="content-html fadein ng-star-inserted" style="position: relative;"><p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">Câu tường thuật là loại câu thuật lại lời nói của một người khác dưới dạng gián tiếp.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></p>

<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">*&nbsp; Thay đổi thì của câu: Thì của các động từ trong lời nói gián tiếp thay đổi theo một nguyên tắc chung là lùi về quá khứ</span></span></p>

<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">* Thay đổi đại từ: Các đại từ nhân xưng và đại sở hữu khi chuyển từ lời nói trực tiếp sang lời nói gián tiếp được thay đổi: ví dụ: I &gt; she/he, we &gt; they</span></span></p>

<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">* Các trạng từ chỉ nơi chốn, thời gian: xem bảng</span></span></p>

<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt"><strong><span style="color:#4472c4">I.&nbsp;Câu tường thuật ở dạng câu kể</span></strong></span></span></p>

<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">S + say(s)/said + (that) + S + V</span></span></p>

<ul>
	<li><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">says/say to + O&nbsp;-&gt;&nbsp;tells/tell + O</span></span></li>
	<li><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">said to + O&nbsp;-&gt;told+O</span></span></li>
</ul>

<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">Eg: He said to me” I haven’t finished my work” -&gt;&nbsp;He told me he hadn’t finished his work.</span></span></p>

<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm">&nbsp;</p>

<table cellspacing="0" class="Table" style="background:white; border-collapse:collapse; border:undefined; width:390.7pt">
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">&nbsp;<strong>Direct speech&nbsp;</strong></span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt"><strong>&nbsp;Reported speech</strong></span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">today</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">that day</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">tonight &nbsp;</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">that night</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">tomorrow&nbsp;</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">the next day / the following day</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">yesterday</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">the day before / the previous day</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">ago</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">before</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">now &nbsp;&nbsp;</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">then</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">next / on Tuesday</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">the next / following Tuesday</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">last Tuesday</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">the previous Tuesday / the Tuesday before</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">the day after tomorrow</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">in two days’ time / two days later</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">this&nbsp;</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">that</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">these</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">those</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">this / that&nbsp;</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">the</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">here &nbsp;</span></span></p>
			</td>
			<td style="background-color:white; height:21.95pt">
			<p style="margin-left:0cm; margin-right:0cm"><span style="font-family:Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif"><span style="font-size:11pt">there</span></span></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>
</div></div>`
  },
  // {id:9,
  // question: `
  // `, options:[
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``],
  // answer:4,
  // explanation:``
  // },
  // {id:9,
  // question: `
  // `, options:[
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``],
  // answer:4,
  // explanation:``
  // },
  // {id:9,
  // question: `
  // `, options:[
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``],
  // answer:4,
  // explanation:``
  // },
  // {id:9,
  // question: `
  // `, options:[
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``],
  // answer:4,
  // explanation:``
  // },
  // {id:9,
  // question: `
  // `, options:[
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``],
  // answer:4,
  // explanation:``
  // },
  // {id:9,
  // question: `
  // `, options:[
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``,
  //     ``],
  // answer:4,
  // explanation:``
  // },
];
